### RUTUJA VIJAY DUKHANDE

**E-Mail:** rutujadukhande17@gmail.com **Phone**: 6823367777 **LinkedIn:** www.linkedin.com/in/RutujaDukhande **GitHub:** https://github.com/Rutuja177

### **SUMMARY**

A software engineering professional with entry-level experience specializing in designing custom software solutions in Python and JavaScript, and Agile software development. A proven track record of executing complex technical projects for implementation of CRM tools.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Developed a responsive website for a local business as part of a class project HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React.js, React Native
- Designed and implemented a small database using SQL, including schema design, table creation, and data insertion MySQL
- Experience working with REST APIs, including retrieving data and integration it into web application from external services PHP,
  Node.is, Postman, Ajax
- Utilized Git branching and merging to create and merge branches, testing and releasing new features GitHub
- Experienced in using XSLT to transform XML data into HTML, ensuring optimal presentation and formatting of data for web applications
- $\bullet \ \ Built\ ML\ models\ such\ as\ linear\ regression,\ classification,\ SVM-OOP\ concepts,\ Python,\ NumPy,\ Pandas,\ SciPy,\ Scikit-learn$
- Developed a personal project where I built and trained a CNN model to classify images of a food dataset with 75% accuracy Python, Jupyter Notebook, ResNet-50, Convolutional neural networks (CNNs)
- Familiarity with NLP techniques, including tokenization, stemming, and stop-word removal to work on dataset of 10,000 tweets Natural Language Toolkit (NLTK)
- Proficient in data Visualization, creating scatter plots, line charts, and other data visualizations to effectively communicate insights from data, and data preprocessing Matplotlib, Seaborn
- Strong soft skill, including communication, organization, problem-solving abilities, project Management, mentorship skills

#### **EDUCATION**

• The University of Texas at Arlington, Arlington

Master of Science in Computer Science – 3.81/4.00

May 2023

• Mumbai University, India

**Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering** 

**July 2019** 

### ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

### **Plant Disease Detection Application**

Created Android app for farmers to analyze diseased plants, with UI development and photo capture feature using React Native. Conducted unit tests and participated in Scrum and SDLC.

## **Car Rental Application**

Built and app that enables users to easily locate available cars based on location and time, which included coding in JavaScript and React, Database Management in MySQL and, creating REST APIs in PHP.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Tech Intern, The Sparks Foundation**

Feb 2019 - April 2019

- Contributed to the development of a payment gateway microservice on AWS EC2 instance
- Conducted web development using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap for the payment gateway interface
- · Assisted in integrating a third-party payment solution into the payment gateway microservice

# Software Engineer, Accenture Services Pvt. Ltd., India

Jan 2020 - July 2021

- · Analyzed business requirements and integrated/enhanced the processes on Veeva CRM and Salesforce
- Designed, developed, and maintained Salesforce application using Apex, Visualforce, and Lightning technologies
- Managed ServiceNow and Implemented JIRA for tracking various bugs and issues
- · Drove new feature development to improve data collection processes for an international client
- · Conducted data manipulation and migration activities on Salesforce for over 30lacs+ records
- · Utilized Agile methodology to work collaboratively with cross-functional teams and prioritize tasks efficiently

# **Graduate Teaching Assistant, UTA**

Aug 2022 – Dec 2022

- Facilitated learning of web application design and development, emphasizing data management and processing
- Evaluated student progress by grading assignments, projects, midterm, and final exams

# **Data Science Teaching Assistant, UTA**

Jan 2022 - present

- Leading weekly labs and providing assistance to undergrad students
- · Holding weekly office hours where students may get help on coding assignments, labs, and any course concepts
- Collaborated with Professor on a research topic, assisted in the development of image classification, contributing to the preprocessing of the image data and achieving a 10% improvement in accuracy